

Akshat Gupta

Software Developer

I'm a Software Developer experienced in Frontend Web Development, Cloud Computing, SEO, Digital Marketing, SEM & Offline Marketing. When I am not coding, I am organising or taking part in workshops, webinars & hackathons, writing blogs, solving doubts and mentoring students.

akshatvg23@gmail.com

Chennai, India

in linkedin.com/in/akshatvg

🧻 github.com/akshatvg

medium.com/@akshatvg

+91 9600093179

akshatvg.com

@akshatvg

stackoverflow.com/users/11494538/akshat-gupta

instagram.com/akshatvg

EDUCATION

University

06/2018 - Present

Information Technology

High School

Chinmaya Vidyalaya, Taylors Road 🗷

06/2004 - 06/2018

PCMC

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Intern

Josh Talks 🗷

08/2020 - Present

Tasks

- Incharge of maintaining Josh Skills, Josh Kosh and DigitalBeti.
- Incharge of managing junior interns, delegating work and coordinating with all teams.

Contact: Harsh Gupta - +919811159680

Full Stack Developer GAIUS Networks ☑

07/2020 - 07/2020

Task

- Incharge of making the official web portal for the company.
- Responsible for making the official web portal for bublr.io, a community engagement PWA.
- Responsible for making the official PWA for Flipped Classrooms. ☑

Contact: Arjuna Sathiaseelan - +447971329880

Software Development Intern

Josh Talks 🗷

06/2020 - 07/2020

Task

 Incharge of making the Josh Skills web portal to improve the brand's organic reach for their courses.

Contact: Harsh Gupta - +919811159680

SKILLS

Web Development Cloud Computing SEO/SEM

Digital Marketing Management WordPress

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Public Speaking Leadership Teamwork

Time Management Adaptability

Event Management

PROJECTS

DigitalBeti (02/2020 - 12/2020) 🗗

 Web portal for DigitalBeti, a joint initiative by Facebook and the Government of India to overcome the digital gender gap in India by training women from rural areas to become entrepreneurs, using digital tools.

 Mobile first website for Josh Skills with an aim to improve the brand's SEO & online presence for their online courses.

speakOut (06/2020 - 06/2020) 🗗

 Web portal to help conduct meetings, livestreams, project reviews & informal hangout sessions in high definition real time video and audio.

Going Online As Leaders (01/2020 - 02/2020) ♂

 Web portal for Going Online As Leaders (GOAL) in association with the Tribal Ministry of India and Josh Talks.

ORGANIZATIONS

CodeChef-VIT (12/2018 - Present) ☑

Technical Chair

Team FootBrawlers (10/2019 - Present) ✓

Management Lead

Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador

Developer Student Clubs VIT (12/2018 - 10/2020) ☑

Inner Circle Member

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (12/2020 - Present) ☑

Credential ID: 63280081

Python (Basic) (09/2020 - Present) ☑

Credential ID: B7D22892D983

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing (07/2020 - Present) ☑

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure (05/2019 - Present) ♂

Credential ID: 7PLZLGHTCPFZ

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend Web Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS, ReactJS, Zurb Foundation, JSON, AJAX, Axios and Redux.

Cloud Computing

Azure, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Heroku and Amazon Web Services (AWS).

Marketing

SEO, SEM, Social Media Marketing, Offline Marketing.

Backend Web Development

PHP and basics of NodeJS & Django.

Competitive Coding

JavaScript, Python, C++, Java.

ACHIEVEMENTS

First Place (VIT Hack 2020) (10/2020)

Won the first place in the Gravitas AI Case partner problem statement as well as the AWS Educate open challenge out of over 1,200 registered participants.

Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award (09/2020)

Awarded the Achiever Award & Special Achiever Award for exemplary performance at various National & International events and in recognition of my academic performance.

Audience's Favourite (RTE Hack 2020) (09/2020)

Won the Audience's Favourite Award by being the top voted and most liked project of the hackathon.honor title

Best Healthcare Hack (Hophacks Fall 2019) (09/2019)

Won the best Healthcare Hack award powered by Siemens Healthineers out of 44 submitted projects.

LANGUAGES

English

Native or Bilinaual Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Tamil

Limited Working Proficiency